Finding Aid for Nabeel Abraham papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical
  - Israel/Israeli
    - Economy, 1985-1992 (Box 11)
    - Elections, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Espionage 9/11, 2002 (Box 11)
    - Intelligence Services, 1990-1994 (Box 11)
    - Justice, 1988-1993 (Box 11)
    - Lobby, 1985-2002 (Box 11)
    - Mentality, 1982-1989 (Box 11)
    - Military Actions, 1981-1991 (Box 11)
    - Museums/Archaeology, 1985-1992 (Box 11)
    - Nukes, 1981-2003; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - And Palestine, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Press Censorship, 1982-1992 (Box 11)
    - Racism, 1986-2004 (Box 11)
    - Rejectionism, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
    - Repression of Intifada, 1986-1993 (Box 11)
    - Settlements, 1981-1992 (Box 11)
    - Settlers, 1982-1991 (Box 11)
    - And South Africa, 1985-1990 (Box 11)
    - Terrorism, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Vatican Relations, 1985-1989 (Box 11)
    - War Plans, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - WMD, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Israelification of U.S. Tactics, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Jabara, Abdeen, 1983-2004; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Jaber, Hassan, 1998; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Jackson, Jesse, 1988-1990 (Box 11)
  - Japan, 1985-1991 (Box 11)
  - Jaws/Exodus, undated (Box 11)
  - JDL/JUDO (Jewish Defense League/Jews United to Defend Ourselves), 1985-1990 (Box 11)
  - Jenin, 2002 (Box 11)
  - Jerusalem, 1990-2001 (Box 11)
  - Jerusalem Embassy Move, 1984-1988 (Box 11)
  - Jewish
    - Denial, 2002 (Box 11)
    - Fundamentalism, 1981-1990 (Box 11)
    - Genetics, 2001 (Box 11)
    - Literature, 2001 (Box 11)
    - Terrorism in Israel, 1984-1990 (Box 11)
  - Jordan, 1983-1991; undated (Box 11)
  - Journalists Attacked, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Judaism on Women, 1982-1994 (Box 11)
  - Judis, John B., 1991 (Box 11)
  - Kahane, Meir, 1982-1990 (Box 11)
  - KAL (Korean Air Lines) 007, 1983-1987 (Box 11)
  - Kassem, Kufr, undated (Box 12)
  - Katarsky, Tony-East Dearborn Research Proposal, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Katz, Sue, undated (Box 12)
  - Kemp, Jack, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Kenan, Amos, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1992 (Box 12)
  - Kibbutz, 1987 (Box 12)
  - "Kill a Raghead for Me,", 2003 (Box 12)
  - King Hussein, 1986-1988 (Box 12)
  - Kingsolver, Barbara, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Kirkpatrick, Jean, 1988-1989 (Box 12)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1987-1992 (Box 12)
  - Klein, Alisa, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Klein, Naomi, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Koch, Ed, 1985-1988 (Box 12)
  - Kollek, Ted, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Kondracke, Morton, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Kopkind Colony, 2003-2004 (Box 12)
  - Korematsu, 2002 (Box 12)
  - Kristallnacht, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Krugman, Paul, 2003-2004 (Box 12)
  - Kufrproof.com, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Kurds, 1987-2002 (Box 12)
  - L.A. Eight, 1987-2003; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Land Attachment, 1988 (Box 12)
  - LAND (Liberal Arts Network for Development) Conference, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Landau Commission, undated (Box 12)
  - Langer, Felicia, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Language of Power, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Lebanon Crisis, 1982-1983; undated (Box 12)
  - Legislative Committee, 1996 (Box 12)
  - LeMay, Curtis, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Levin, Carl, 1980-1990 (Box 12)
  - Lewis, Anthony, 1982-1993 (Box 12)
  - Lewis, Bernard, 1990-2004 (Box 12)
  - Lewis, Flora, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Libyan Student Arrests, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Looting, 1996-2003 (Box 12)
  - Lubavitchers, 1990-1996 (Box 12)
  - Madonna University, 1996-1997; undated (Box 12)
  - Mahfouz, Naguib, 1990 undated (Box 12)
  - Makiya, Kanan, 1992-1993 (Box 12)
  - Mandela, Nelson, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Mapam, 1984-1988 (Box 12)
  - Mapping Arab Diasporas, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Mass Culture and Social Decay, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Mattawa, Khaled, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Media
    - Arab Drug Connection, 1982-1984 (Box 12)
    - Arab Sheik Stereotypes, 1979-1985 (Box 12)
    - Arab Terrorist Stereotype in U.S., 1979-1985 (Box 12)
    - Complicity, 2003-2004 (Box 12)
    - Double Standard, 1980-1987 (Box 12)
    - General, 1980-2004; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - MESA (Middle Eastern Studies Association), 1982 (Box 12)
  - MESA (Middle Eastern Studies Association) Conference, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Michigan Academy of Science, 1988-1989 (Box 12)
  - Michigan Pension Fund, 1985-1987 (Box 12)
  - Microsoft Encarta Encyclopedia, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Middle East Forum, 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-1979; undated (Box 12)
  - Molested World, 2003 undated (Box 12)
  - Moral Callousness, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Moral Monsters, 2002 (Box 12)
  - Morality/Moral Systems, 1985-1988 (Box 12)
  - Morris, Benny, 1992-2004 (Box 12)
  - Moyers, Bill, 1991-2004 (Box 12)
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1990 undated (Box 12)
  - MSU (Michigan State University) Press, 2000-2003 (Box 12)
  - Musawi Assassination, 1992 (Box 12)
  - Museums/Libraries, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Musings, 1980-2005 (Box 12)
  - Muslim Double Standard, 2002 (Box 12)
  - Muslims, 2000-2002 (Box 12)
  - Myths, 1990-1992 (Box 12)
  - Naber, Nadine, 1998-2003 (Box 12)
  - Nader, Support by, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Nassiriya, 2003 (Box 13)
  - Nasser, Gamal: 1955 Peace Offer, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Nation of Islam, 2002 (Box 13)
  - National Council of Churches, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Nazis (Bitburg), 1983-1988 (Box 13)
  - NEH (National Endowment for the Humanities)
    - HFCC, 1994 (Box 13)
    - Readings, 1994 undated (Box 13)
  - Netanyahu, Benjamin, 1990-1991 (Box 13)
  - New Jewish Agenda, 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - New Orleans, 1997 (Box 13)
  - New Republic, 1986-1993 (Box 13)
  - New York Times, 1990-1991
    - Corrections, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Coverage of Intifada Since, August 1990; 1989-1990 (Box 13)
    - Editorials, 1986-1992 (Box 13)
    - General, 1987-1991 (Box 13)
  - The New Yorker, Mark Singer, 2001 (Box 13)
  - Newsday, 1990-1991 (Box 13)
  - Newsletter-Center for Near Eastern Studies (University of Michigan), undated (Box 13)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1988-1990 (Box 13)
  - No Negotiations, 2003 (Box 13)
  - No WMD Evidence, 2003-2004 (Box 13)
  - Non-Violence, 2001-2002 (Box 13)
  - North Korea, 2002-2003 (Box 13)
  - North Yemen, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Notes, 1983 undated (Box 13)
  - Noula, 1996 (Box 13)
  - Nuclear Proliferation, 1987-1992 (Box 13)
  - OAH (Organization of American Historians), 2002 (Box 13)
  - OAS (Organization of Arab Students), 1972 undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Obituaries, 2002-2005 (Box 13)
  - O'Brien, Conor Cruise, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Occupied Territories: Apartheid, 1987 (Box 13)
  - Odeh, Alex, 1985-1987 (Box 13)
  - Oil, 2001-2004 (Box 13)
  - Okdie Affair, 1984-1990; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Oklahoma Bombing, 1995 (Box 13)
  - Ollman, Bartell, 2005 (Box 13)
  - O'Neil, John, 1991 (Box 13)
  - Opinion Polls, 1982-1990 (Box 13)
  - Opposition, 2003 (Box 13)
  - Orfalea, Gregory, 1988-1989 (Box 13)
  - Orwell's "Marrakech", 1989 (Box 13)
  - Oslo
    - Criticism, 1992-1993; undated (Box 13)
    - Developments, 1993 (Box 13)
    - General, 1995-1998; undated; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - PLO Propaganda, 1993 (Box 13)
    - Police Force, 1993 (Box 13)
  - Ozick, Cynthia, 1988-1989; undated (Box 13)
  - Palestine
    - Academic Center, 1972-1978; undated (Box 13)
    - Center for the Study of Nonviolence, 1985-1988 (Box 13)
    - Day, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Information Office Closing, 1987-1988 (Box 13)
    - National Council-Algeria, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Solidarity Workshop, 1988 (Box 14)
    - State, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Palestinian Politics, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Palestinians
    - Arrested in U.S., 1993 (Box 14)
    - Collaborators, 1989-1992 (Box 14)
    - Demographics, 1984-1992 (Box 14)
  - Parsons, Talcott, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Patriot Missiles, 1992-1993 (Box 14)
  - Peace Process, 1982-1992; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Peace Talks, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
  - Peled, Matti (General), 1982 (Box 14)
  - Peres, Shimon, 1985-1989 (Box 14)
  - Perle, Richard, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Perlmutter, Amos, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Peru, 1990 (Box 14)
  - Petitions and Open Letters, 1987-2004 (Box 14)
  - Pew Research Muslim American Survey, 2007 (Box 14)
  - Pilger, John, 2004 (Box 14)
  - PLO (Palestine Liberation Organization)
    - Contacts with U.S., 1984-1988 (Box 14)
    - General, 1982-1991 (Box 14)
    - Jordan, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Terrorism, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Podhoretz, Norman, 1985-1989 (Box 14)
  - Politicians and Arab Stereotypes, 1982-2000 (Box 14)
  - Politics, 1982-1987 (Box 14)
  - Polls, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Post Road Map, 2003-2005 (Box 14)
  - Post-War Iraq, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Powell, Colin, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Proposals, 1983 undated (Box 14)
  - Publishing Outlets, 2002-2004 (Box 14)
  - Pulera, Dominic, 2001-2004 (Box 14)
  - Qat, 1992-1993 (Box 14)
  - Quran, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Rabin, Yitzhak, 1988-1992 (Box 14)
  - Racialization Book, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Racism (France), 1986-1995 (Box 14)
  - Radius of Arab American Writers (RAWI), 2007 (Box 14)
  - Ragheb, Fiona, 1994-1998 (Box 14)
  - Ramadan, Tariq, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Reagan Peace Plan, 1981-1989 (Box 14)
  - Recommendation Letters, 1983-1990 (Box 14)
  - Redgrave, Vanessa, 1984-1987 (Box 14)
  - Red-Neds Support, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Reinhart, Tanya-Analysis, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Religion, 1989 undated (Box 14)
  - Researchers on Arab-Americans, 1982-2003 (Box 14)
  - Resolution 242, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Retirement, 2013 (Box 14)
  - Reviews
    - Fateful Triangle, undated (Box 14)
    - International Journal of Middle East Studies, 2001 (Box 14)
    - Middle East Journal, 1987 (Box 14)
  - Right of Return, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Road Map
    - Critiques, 2003 (Box 14)
    - Documentation, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Robertson, Pat, 1986-1988 (Box 14)
  - Robinson, Richard, undated (Box 14)
  - Rodinson, Maxime, undated (Box 14)
  - Rolling Stone, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Rosenthal, A.M., 1988-1992 (Box 14)
  - Ruling Iraq, 2003-2004 (Box 14)
  - Rumsfeld, Donald, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Sabbatical, 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Saddam CBS Interview, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Safire, William, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Safran, Nadav, 1985-1986 (Box 14)
  - Said, Edward
    - General, 1973-2003; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - General, 1973-2003; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Obituaries, 2003-2004 (Box 15)
    - Remembered, 2003-2004 (Box 15)
    - Roadmap, 2000-2003 (Box 15)
  - Salafis, 2002 (Box 15)
  - Sanctions, 1976-1992 (Box 15)
  - Sartawi, Issam, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Saudi/Israel Alliance, 1992-1993 (Box 15)
  - Saudi Peace Plan, 2002 (Box 15)
  - Science Board Report, 2004 (Box 15)
  - Scott, Jon, 1988-1989 (Box 15)
  - Secrest, William, 2003 (Box 15)
  - Secret Evidence, 2001 (Box 15)
  - Settlements, 1994-2003 (Box 15)
  - Sex, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Shahak, Israel
    - Correspondence
      - 1985-1992 (Box 15)
      - 1993-1999 (Box 15)
    - General, 1987-2003; 5 folders (Box 15)
    - Works, 1987-1997; 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Shain, Yossi, 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Shamir, Israel, 2001-2002; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Shamir, Yitshak (Box 16)
    - Election Plan, 1989; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - General, 1986-1991 (Box 16)
  - Sharon, Ariel
    - vs. Army, 2003-2004 (Box 16)
    - And Bush Plan, 2004 (Box 16)
    - General, 1985-1989 (Box 16)
    - War, 2002 (Box 16)
  - Shayota, Athir, 1993-1995 (Box 16)
  - Shell, Kim, 2002 (Box 16)
  - Shin Beth, 1984-1992 (Box 16)
  - Shock and Awe, 1996-2003 (Box 16)
  - Shultz, George, 1982-1993 (Box 16)
  - Slade, Shelley, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Smear Campaigns, 1979-1981 (Box 16)
  - Smith, John, 1990 (Box 16)
  - South Africa, 1986-1993 (Box 16)
  - South Yemen, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Sports/Empire, 2003 (Box 16)
  - State Farm, 1990 undated (Box 16)
  - State of the Union, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Stockton, Ronald, 1994 undated (Box 16)
  - Stone, I.F., 1989 (Box 16)
  - Student Appreciation Notes, 2004 undated (Box 16)
  - Suicide Bombings, 2002-2004 (Box 16)
  - Suleiman, Michael, 1982-1997 (Box 16)
  - Support for Arab and Muslim Americans-9/11/2001 (Box 16)
  - Supreme Court, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Syllabi, 1974-2006 (Box 16)
  - Syria
    - Attack on, 2003 (Box 16)
    - Campaign Against, 1986 (Box 16)
    - General, 1984-1992 (Box 16)
    - And Iran, 2003 (Box 16)
    - Missile Crisis, 1986 (Box 16)
  - TABA, 1986 undated (Box 16)
  - Tactical Nukes, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Target Assassination, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Targeting Arab Americans Post 9/11, 2002 (Box 16)
  - Temple Mount, 1986-1993 (Box 16)
  - Terrorism in U.S. (Arab), 1986-1988 (Box 16)
  - Terrorism References, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Terry, Janice, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Textbook Studies, 1975-1981 (Box 16)
  - Thanksgiving and Muslims, 2001-2003 (Box 16)
  - The Thirty Year Itch, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Timerman, Jacobo, 1988 undated (Box 16)
  - Tobacco, 1991-1993 (Box 16)
  - Toledo Arab Americans, 1985; 2000 (Box 16)
  - Torture
    - General, 1979-2003 (Box 16)
    - In Occupied Territories and Israel, 1979-1993 (Box 16)
    - And Targeted Killings, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Travel Notebook, undated (Box 16)
  - Tsemel, Lea, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Tunis Radio, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Turkey, 1992-2003 (Box 16)
  - Turki, Fawaz, 1994 (Box 16)
  - UC Irvine (University of California, Irvine) Conference, 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - United Community Services, 1974-1985 (Box 16)
  - United Holy Land Fund, 1980 (Box 16)
  - United Nations (Box 17)
    - 242 (Security Council Resolution), 1989-1992 (Box 17)
    - Inspections, U.S. Deception, 2003-2004 (Box 17)
  - United States
    - Aid to Israel, 1983-2002 (Box 17)
    - Assistance to Saddam, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
    - Commission on Civil Rights: Arab-Americans, 1987 (Box 17)
    - Double Standard, 1987-1988 (Box 17)
    - Involvement in Middle East, 1982-1984 (Box 17)
    - Military, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
    - Propaganda, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
    - Saber Rattling-9/11/01, 2001-2002 (Box 17)
    - In United Nations, 1985-2003 (Box 17)
    - War Plans, 2003 (Box 17)
    - WMD (Weapons of Mass Destruction), 2003 (Box 17)
  - United Way, 1997 (Box 17)
  - University of Michigan
    - Director Position, Center for Arab American Studies, 2001-2004 (Box 17)
    - Political Assimilation of Arab Americans, 1997 (Box 17)
  - Van Creveld, Martin, 2004 (Box 17)
  - Vanunu, Mordechai, 1986-2004; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Vidal, Gore, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Violence and Harassment of Arabs, 1978-1987 (Box 17)
  - Vita
    - Documentation, 1978-2002 (Box 17)
    - References, 1977-2003 (Box 17)
  - Wagons West, circa, 2002 (Box 17)
  - The Wall, 2003-2004 (Box 17)
  - War on Terror, 2002 (Box 17)
  - War Reports, 2003 (Box 17)
  - "War in the Wings"-MEI (Middle East Institute), 1986 (Box 17)
  - Water, 1989-1995 (Box 17)
  - Wetlands, 1991 (Box 17)
  - When Democracy Failed, 2003 (Box 17)
  - Who is an Arab?, 2004 (Box 17)
  - Wiesel, Elie, 1986-1987 (Box 17)
  - Wieseltier, Leon, 1988 (Box 17)
  - Witch Hunt, 2003 (Box 17)
  - Wolfowitz, Paul, 2003 (Box 17)
  - Womack, Mary, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Writers/Poets, 1998-2004 (Box 17)
  - Yassin, Ahmed, 2004 (Box 17)
  - Yemenis, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Zaire, 1991-1992 (Box 17)
  - Ziad Abu Eain, 1981; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Zionism, 1981-1998 (Box 17)
  - Zogby, James, 1986-2004; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Zogby, James, 1986-2004 (Box 27)
- Writings
  The Writings series (2.5 linear feet) consists mostly of papers and articles Abraham wrote on Arab American and Middle East issues. There are also a few fictional pieces, such as "The Temptation of Lugman Abdallah" and several research proposals. Also included in this series is correspondence with publishers.
  - Against the Current, 1991-2000 (Box 18)
  - Al-Jaliyah, 1979 (Box 18)
  - "Arab-American Marginality: Mythos and Praxis"
    - Background Materials, 1979-1987 (Box 18)
    - Paper, 1989 (Box 18)
  - "Arabs in America: an Overview,", 1981 (Box 18)
  - "Arabs in America: the View from HFCC,", 1988 (Box 18)
  - The Arab World and Arab-Americans: Understanding a Neglected Minority, 1981 (Box 18)
  - "Cat in the Gut,", 1997 (Box 18)
  - Chomsky Birthday, 1998 (Box 18)
  - "Conflict and Control in an American Mosque: the Politics of Gender,", 1984-1993; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - The Connection, 1985 (Box 18)
  - "The Conversion of Chairman Arafat,", 1989 (Box 18)
  - Cranbrook Peace Foundation, 1990-1991 (Box 18)
  - Detroit Free Press Handbook, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Encyclopedia of the American Left, 1988-1997 (Box 18)
  - Encyclopedia of World Cultures, 1989-1990; undated (Box 18)
  - "The Fifty-Foot Woman,", 2004 (Box 18)
  - Gale Research, 1993-1996 (Box 18)
  - Georgetown Conference: "In Search of Identity: Reflections on the Arab Community of Detroit,", 1997 (Box 18)
  - "Ideology, Politics and Factionalism Among Yemeni Immigrants in Detroit,", 1982 (Box 18)
  - "Imperfect Storm: Israel Shamir and His Critics,", 2001 (Box 18)
  - "The Influence of Yemeni National Politics on a Yemeni Community Abroad: Political Conflict and Schism in Detroit,", 1981 (Box 18)
  - Invarianti, 1989 (Box 18)
  - "Islamic Fundamentalism in the U.S. Media,", 1992 (Box 18)
  - Komisar, Bobbie, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Lies of Our Times
    - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Materials, 1989-1994; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Issues
      - 1990-1991 (Box 18)
      - 1992-1993 (Box 18)
  - MERIP/Middle East Report, 1977-1990 (Box 19)
  - Metro Times, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Michigan Gardener Newsletter, undated (Box 19)
  - Microsoft Encarta Encyclopedia, 1996-2001 (Box 19)
  - Middle East International, 1982-1986 (Box 19)
  - Mideast Monitor-"Covering Israel's Bomb,", 1986-1987 (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978-1989 (Box 19)
  - The Muslim World: "From Baghdad to New York: Young Muslims on War and Terrorism,", 2003-2005 (Box 19)
  - New Outlook: "Reflections on Israel and Palestine After Lebanon,", 1982-1983 (Box 19)
  - "On the Road with Bob: Peddling in the Early Sixties,", 1998 (Box 19)
  - "To Palestine and Back: Quest for Place,", 1998-2000 (Box 19)
  - "Position Paper on the Present and Future Directions of the Association: a Critique and Proposal" (AAUG), 1980 (Box 19)
  - "The Prospects for Peace in Lebanon and the Middle East,", 1981 (Box 19)
  - Research Proposals
    - "A Comprehensive Multi-Cultural, Multi-Purpose, Multi-Year Resource-Curriculum Development Project...,", 1981 (Box 19)
    - "A Study of the Socio-Cultural and Religious Adjustment of the Arab-Muslim Community of the United States, 1948-1980", 1981-1983 (Box 19)
    - "Addressing the Educational Needs of Arab-American Students in Dearborn: A School Improvement Program,", 1982 (Box 19)
    - "Curriculum Materials on the Arab World,", 1982 (Box 19)
    - "Development and Dissemination of Cross-Cultural Instructional Materials about Middle East Peoples and Culture,", 1983 (Box 19)
  - "Road Map to Sharonville,", 2003 (Box 19)
  - Sada Alwatan, 1986-1988 (Box 19)
  - Shahak Commentary, 1995-1996 (Box 19)
  - "The Southend: an Arab Muslim Working-Class Community,", 1983 (Box 19)
  - South End Press, 1991-1993 (Box 19)
  - Student Papers, 1971-1976 (Box 19)
  - "Tales of Qaddafi, Reagan, and Syrian Missiles,", 1986 (Box 19)
  - "The Temptation of Lugman Abdallah,", 2004 (Box 19)
  - "Turned Inside Out: Memories of an Arab Muslim Childhood,", 2001-2004; undated; 3 folders (Box 19)
  - University of Michigan Press, 1990-1993 (Box 20)
  - "The Yemen: People and Society, A Background Paper Prepared for Abdeen Jabara, Attorney-at-Law", 1980-1997 (Box 20)
  - "The Yemeni Immigrant Community of Detroit: Background, Emigration, and Community Life,", 1980 (Box 20)
- Dissertation
  The Dissertation series (2 linear feet) includes materials relating to Abraham's dissertation completed at the University of Michigan and entitled "National and Local Politics: a Study of Political Conflict in the Yemeni Immigrant Community of Detroit, Michigan." It primarily examines the impact of political developments in Yemen on politics in the Yemeni immigrant community in Detroit, particularly the differences between those of northern and southern origin. In addition to a copy of the dissertation itself are materials including newspapers, newsletters, and other publications, many of them in Arabic and produced by Yemeni organizations, as well as Abraham's field notes, which contain notes from interviews conducted with members of the Yemeni community in Detroit.
  - "26th September" Newspaper, undated (Box 20)
  - Arab Workers and Arab Community in U.S., 1962-1977; undated (Box 20)
  - Arabic-Language Materials (1 of 4), undated (Box 20)
  - Arabic-Language Materials (2 of 4), undated (Box 20)
  - Arabic-Language Materials (3 of 4), undated (Box 20)
  - Arabic-Language Materials (4 of 4), undated (Box 20)
  - Arbitration Committee (Political Factions), undated (Box 20)
  - Audio Cassettes, 1976 (Box 20)
  - Banking, 1976 undated (Box 20)
  - Chapter 1 Materials, 1973-1986; undated (Box 20)
  - Chapter 6 Materials, 1976 undated (Box 20)
  - Chrysler Training Program, 1975 undated (Box 20)
  - Communiques and Bulletins (Non-Yemeni), 1976 undated (Box 20)
  - Dearborn (1 of 2), 1973-1978; undated (Box 20)
  - Dearborn (2 of 2), 1973-1978; undated (Box 20)
  - Dissertation
    - Outline, 1977 undated (Box 20)
    - "National and Local Politics: a Study of Political Conflict in the Yemeni Immigrant Community of Detroit, Michigan", 1978; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Factionalism, 1967-1978; undated (Box 20)
  - Field Notes (1 of 5), 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Field Notes (2 of 5), 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Field Notes (3 of 5), 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Field Notes (4 of 5), 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Field Notes (5 of 5), 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Field Work, undated (Box 21)
  - Immigration-Illegal, 1974-1977 (Box 21)
  - Index Cards (1 of 2), undated (Box 21)
  - Index Cards (2 of 2), undated (Box 21)
  - International Institute Files, 1970-1976 (Box 21)
  - Interview Schedules-Originals, 1975 undated (Box 21)
  - Interviews with Yemenis, undated (Box 21)
  - Labor and Migration, 1977 undated (Box 21)
  - Language Problems, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Leftist North Yemenis (Political Factions), 1976-1977; undated (Box 21)
  - Legal Problems, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Letter of Introduction, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Maps of Yemen, undated (Box 21)
  - Medical Problems, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-1981 (Box 21)
  - Political Factions, 1968-1983 (Box 21)
  - "The Register"-Bulletin of The Organization of Revolutionary Yemeni Resistors, undated (Box 21)
  - Research Proposal, 1975 undated (Box 21)
  - Sameer's Notes, undated (Box 21)
  - Social Structure, undated (Box 21)
  - South Yemen History, 1976 undated (Box 21)
  - Student Records, 1975-1977 (Box 21)
  - UFW (United Farm Workers), 1975 (Box 21)
  - Union of Yemeni Emigres, circa 1977 (Box 21)
  - The Union and Yemenis, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Yemen
    - Arab Association of Detroit (Political Factions)
      - Hamtramck, 1975-1976; undated (Box 21)
      - Salina, 1976 undated (Box 21)
    - Benevolent Association (Political Factions), 1976 undated (Box 21)
  - Yemeni
    - Arab Workers of Detroit, 1974 (Box 21)
    - Communities in U.S., undated (Box 21)
    - Killings in Detroit, 1976 undated (Box 21)
    - National Politics, 1970-1977; undated; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - AAUG (Association of Arab-American University Graduates)-Oslo, 1993 (Box 22)
  - ACCESS (Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services), 1998 (Box 22)
  - ADC (American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee)
    - General, 1981 undated (Box 22)
    - Students, Ann Arbor, 1998-1999 (Box 22)
    - Yemeni Politics Panel, 1987 (Box 22)
  - Anti-War Rally/Teach-Ins, 1990-2003 (Box 22)
  - Arab Culture and Democracy, 1982 (Box 22)
- Lectures and Presentations